<Document>
  # Малые антагонисты

  Большинство, если не все, второстепенные антагонисты - это управляемые призраками роли, которые дают мертвецам новые способы устроить хаос на станции. Они возникают в результате случайных событий.

  # Ревенант

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobRevenant" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Ectoplasm" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Revenants are ethereal beings made of ectoplasm that haunt the crew and steal [color=#8f63e6]life essence[/color] from them.
  - Your essence is your very own [bold]life force[/bold]. Taking damage reduces your essence.
  - Essence is also spent to use [bold]abilities[/bold].
  - To gain essence you first [bold]inspect[/bold] various souls for their worth. More worthy souls grant more essence. Then you must [bold]siphon[/bold] it either when the victim is crit, dead or asleep. All of this is done with [color=yellow][bold][keybind="Use"][/bold][/color].
  - [bold]Stolen essence[/bold] is used to purchase new abilities to incapacitate the crew easier.
  - You are [bold]vulnerable[/bold] to attacks when you siphon a soul or use an ability. You can tell when you are vulnerable when you have a [color=#8f63e6][italic]Corporeal[/italic][/color] status effect.

  ## Эссенция

  - Ваша [color=#a4885c]эссенция[/color] - это ваша собственная жизненная сила и способ использовать способности за определенную плату, не позволяйте ей упасть до 0.
  - Чтобы получить [color=#a4885c]эссенцию[/color], вы сначала проверяете различные души на предмет их ценности. Более достойные души дают больше эссенции.
  Однако просто проверить их ценность недостаточно для сбора [color=#a4885c]эссенции[/color]. Вы должны поглотить её, когда жертва находится в критическом состоянии, мертва или спит.
  - Хорошее начало - пойти в медпункт или жилые помещения, но будьте осторожны, вы уязвимы для атак, когда поглощаете душу. Получение урона уменьшает вашу [color=#a4885c]эссенцию[/color]! Поэтому планируйте свои атаки с умом.

  ## Магазин и силы

  - Используя [color=#a4885c]украденную эссенцию[/color], полученную при поглощении душ, вы можете получить в магазине навыки для таких злоключений, как разрушение окружающей среды, отключение электричества и поражение током.
  - Использование способностей на некоторое время делает вас уязвимым для атак, поэтому планируйте всё заранее и готовьтесь перед атакой.

  # Крысиный король

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobRatKing" Scale="2.4" Caption="The Rat King"/>
  </Box>

  Rat kings are abnormally large rodents capable of [color=yellow]raising huge rat armies[/color] by eating equally huge amounts of food.
  - You have several abilities that come at the cost of your [bold]hunger.[/bold]
  - One such ability is [color=yellow][italic]Raise Army[/italic][/color], which summons a [bold]Rat Servant[/bold]. You can [bold]command[/bold] your servants to stay in place, follow you, attack a target of your choice or attack indiscriminately.
  - You can conjure a cloud of [color=#77b58e]ammonia[/color] using [color=purple][italic]Rat King's Domain[/italic][/color]. This purple gas is mildly poisonous to humans but heals rats.
  - [color=#9daa98][italic]Rummage[/italic][/color] through a disposal unit by using the context menu. Use this to find [bold]scraps of food[/bold] to grow your army.
  - Besides your abilities, [bold]you are stronger than most other animals.[/bold] You and your servants are capable of speech and you're both small enough to fit under airlocks and tables.
  - [bold]Your underlings are still very fragile![/bold] Beware of spacings, explosions and the buisness end of a melee weapon.

  ## Способности

  За способности приходится расплачиваться голодом Крысиного короля. Простой приём пищи восполняет его.

  <Box>
   <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobMouse" Caption="Обычная мыша"/>
   <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobRatServant" Caption="Крысиный слуга"/>
  </Box>
  - Вырастить армию [color=#a4885c]слуг-крыс[/color].
  - Вызвать облако аммиака.

  # Космический дракон

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobDragon" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Космический дракон - это гигантский дракон, который создаёт космические разломы и поедает экипаж.

  ## Способности

  - Пожирать мёртвых жертв, или в критическом состоянии.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobCarp" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CarpRift" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobCarp" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Space dragons are giant extradimensional fish that can [color=red]eat crew[/color] and create [color=#4b7fcc]carp rifts.[/color]
  - Dragons have powerful jaws that allow them to [color=red][italic]Devour[/italic][/color] infrastructure such as doors, windows, and walls.
  - They can also heal themselves by using [color=red][italic]Devour[/italic][/color] on crew members that have gone unconscious or have died.
  - Your [color=orange][italic]Dragon's Breath[/italic][/color] is a [bold]flaming projectile[/bold] which travels a straight flight path, exploding multiple times and igniting things along the way. Try not to hit your carps with this!
  - You have the ability to [color=#4b7fcc][italic]Summon a Carp Rift[/italic][/color]. Rifts periodically spawn [bold]space carp[/bold] and charge up energy over a period of 5 minutes, [bold]which is when it's vulnerable.[/bold] After 5 minutes, it becomes invulnerable and will continue summoning carp as long as the dragon lives.
  - You'll suffer a [bold]temporary debilitating feedback effect[/bold] if one of your rifts are destroyed before it's done charging.
  - If a period of five minutes passes since your spawn or since the last time a rift was charging, [bold]you'll disappear.[/bold]
  - Dragons who have the maximum of 3 fully charged rifts will [bold]never disappear[/bold], but they are still mortal.

  ## Carp Rifts

  - Space Dragons may have up to three Carp Rifts active at any given time.
  - Carp Rifts spawn a [color=#a4885c]Space Carp[/color] every thirty seconds while active.
  - Rifts charge with extradimensional energy over a period of five minutes and are vulnerable during this time. Protect them! The space dragon will suffer a temporary debilitating feedback effect in the event that its rifts are destroyed before they are done charging.
  - You may only charge one rift at any given time.
  - After the rifts are done charging, they are invulnerable and will continue to spawn [color=#a4885c]Space Carp[/color] so long as the Dragon lives.
  - If a period of five minutes passes since the appearance of the Space Dragon or the last time a Carp Rift was charging and unless the Space Dragon already controls the maximum of three Carp Rifts, the Space Dragon will disappear.

  Slimes and spiders have no remarkable features, but will [color=cyan]infest the station[/color] from time to time regardless. Both will give chase and attack anything they see.
  - Slimes may [bold]deal extra cellular or poison damage[/bold], based upon their color. Water hurts them just as it would hurt a slime person.
  - Spiders have a venomous bite and can [bold]create webs[/bold] that are hard to move though. Webs are easily destroyed with a blade. They can also pry open airlocks.
</Document>
